Guide to the Samuel Steward Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- June 2012 Acquisition, 1930-2003; 20.17; (30 boxes)
  - Steward, tattoo materials, 2 (Box 7)
  - Steward, tattoo photographs (Box 7)
  - Collection of matchbooks with Sparrow logos (Box 7)
  - "Tattoo tracings," several hundred original tattoo sketches, including homoerotic tracings and drawings for various Steward projects, 3 (Box 7)
  - Color drawings by Steward, including homoerotic tracings and drawings for various Steward projects (Box 7)
  - Steward appointment calendars for 1965-1987, 7 (Box 7)
  - Steward appointment calendars for (Sex calendar) 1970 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Phil Andros brochure (Box 7)
  - Mimeographed erotic stories and Orejudos drawings, aka pages passed - Black binder titled "Family Bible" (Box 7)
  - Small copper engraved box with design by Steward (Box 7)
  - Autograph book (Box 7)
  - Polaroids in wooden box (Box 14)
  - "Phil Sparrow, tattoo artist" advertisment board (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Original sheet music from Menendez - matted (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - "Polaroid" - matted (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - "Fuck me" photograph - matted (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Typed letter signed from Darrell Inabnit to Steward - matted, 1981 April 22 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Envelope addressed from Zeis School of Tattooing to Phil Sparrow, 1950 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Philip Sparrow "On Gertrude Stein" - 1 page, typescript, matted (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Photograph signed by Fernand Nault[?] - matted (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - "Polaroids" [explicit] - matted (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Typed letter signed from George Platt Lynes - matted, 1954 June 10 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Autographed photograph of Gerry Leavitt - matted (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Unidentified letter and photograph [Thornton Wilder?] - matted, 1937 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Tattoo Club of America, certificate of merit given to Phil Sparrow - matted, 1965 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - Limerick notebook (Box 8)
  - Gay bar notebook (Box 8)
  - "Tattooing and sex" manuscript, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook with clippings (Box 8)
  - "Some notes on how to be an S, for them as wants to be" - typescript, 1 page (Box 8)
  - Rudolph Valentino postcard (blank) and envelope (Box 8)
  - "An Evening with Mam'selle Victoire", 1981 September 17 (Box 8)
  - "Phone list", 1990 November 8 (Box 8)
  - "What this particular M likes" - typescript, 1 page (Box 8)
  - Drummer magazine, issue 21 (Box 8)
  - Holograph letter from "Ella" (Box 8)
  - Fliers for memorial for Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Tolkas, 1983 May 30 (Box 8)
  - Typescript with revisions - 1 page (Box 8)
  - "Eyeglasses by Phillips" - case with monocle (Box 8)
  - Steward tax returns, 5 (Box 8)
  - Interest and dividends notebook, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Schults, Danny, poems, assorted memorabilia, corrected typescript - 276 pages, 2 (Box 8)
  - Guide to Rome and map of Rome, 1950s (Box 8)
  - Steward, the Tattoo Jungle (draft), 2 (Box 8)
  - "Recollections of a Mary Ann" - photocopy (Box 8)
  - 216 polaroid photographs - 3 black zip binders, un-mounted [sexually explicit], 3 (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - Steward, memoirs of Gide and Lord Alfred Douglas, as printed in Gaysweek newspapers, 1978 (Box 9)
  - Marotta, Toby, PhD, "Males Doing Sex Work in the San Francisco Bay Area: A Typology and Description" - typescript, 1988 December 22 (Box 9)
  - Steward, Different Strokes "reader's copy" - Assorted photocopies making up rough draft of manuscript photocopies, 2 (Box 9)
  - Steward, "Sam's Brother" (Box 9)
  - Steward, "Sam's Brother," apparently photocopy of My Brother, Myself with Steward notes and corrections (Box 9)
  - Steward, Murder is Murder is Murder typescript - Half in photocopy and half original manuscript, with holograph corrections, 2 (Box 9)
  - Steward, Chapters from an Autobiography, "dies, signatures, book" galleys, 2 (Box 9)
  - Setward, Chapters from an Autobiography, typescript with holography collections, 2 (Box 9)
  - Drawing sketchbook (address on N. Kenmore) (Box 9)
  - Steward, drawing sketchbook - 4 pages drawings (Box 9)
  - Sketchbook, "Bastille Day, St. Germain du Pres...1950", circa 1950 (Box 9)
  - Phillip Sparrow tattoo advertisment (Box 9)
  - Clippings, 1963 (Box 9)
  - Hells Angels calling card (Box 9)
  - Rustica pizza magnet (Box 9)
  - Tattoo-related photos - Numerous, various sizes (Box 9)
  - 4 misc. photos of Steward, other men (Box 9)
  - Drummer magazine, issue 85, STH magazine no. 43 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous ephemera (Box 9)
  - Phil Sparrow and Samuel Steward stationery (Box 9)
  - Phil Sparrow, Samuel Steward and Privacy, Ltd. cards, 2 (Box 9)
  - Passports and other identification cards, business cards (Box 9)
  - Holograph travel diary, 1937 (Box 9)
  - Holograph travel diary, 1950 (Box 9)
  - A Pair of Roses, by Samuel Steward, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Love Poems: Homage to Housman, by Samuel Steward, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Wooden plaque - Phi Beta Kappa, Ohio State University, 1931 May 28; 2 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Wooden plaque - Ohio State Ph.D., 1934 June 11 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Steward, Bad Boys testimonials ad/promo (Box 10)
  - Steward/Martin correspondence (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Orejudos, Locker Room Series (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Burke article/scandal (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Michael Williams, letter to Martin with Locker Room photocopy, 1995 (Box 10)
  - J. Brian info (Martin) including rare magazine articles on "The Male House of Prostitution" and original prospectuses saved by Martin of the J. Brian stable of hustlers (Box 10)
  - Steward obituaries (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Steward profiles (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Unclassifiable clips (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Autobiography, Sammy excerpts and others (Martin) (Box 10)
  - "Steward collection" inventory (Martin), 1989 (Box 10)
  - Steward reviews (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Original Sam Steward manuscript "Narcissus" ["On Andros Island"] (Box 10)
  - Preston Stuff (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Steward's reviews, "Saki" (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Steward, Gay Sunshine Interview (Martin) (Box 10)
  - Steward, Vector, Drummer and Stallion magazines (Martin) - [ Drummer missing] (Box 10)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, cards to Steward, occasional holograph notes, brochures, general ephemera, 17 (Box 10)
  - Ceramic plaque (Box 18)
  - Anchor tattoo stamp (Box 18)
  - Arizona highway patrol badge (Box 18)
  - Carved wood finial (Box 18)
  - Roman Conquests, corrected proofs - 637 pages, several states, 2 (Box 11)
  - Murder is Murder, corrected holograph edits - Bound, 189 pages (Box 11)
  - Page proofs, Greek Ways, 2 (Box 11)
  - Page proofs, Shuttlecock (Box 11)
  - Shuttlecock, holograph-corrected proofs (Box 11)
  - Boys in Blue, corrected proofs, 2 (Box 11)
  - Parisian Lives, corrected typescripts, 2 (Box 11)
  - Unsorted corrected proofs and manuscripts, 3 (Box 11)
  - Chapters from an Autobiography, galleys, proofs, correspondence, specimen settings, 3 (Box 11)
  - Greek Ways manuscript with corrections - Photocopy (Box 11)
  - Below the Belt, typescript with holograph corrections (Box 11)
  - Steward, original holograph manuscript of "West Virginia"/"Ellenhurst" novel, 2 (Box 12)
  - The Tattoo Jungle manuscript - photocopied, 2 (Box 12)
  - "Sam" and "Phil" miniature California license plates (Box 12)
  - The Bluejackets Manual, 1940 (Box 12)
    Includes three video cassettes: Rick X talks to Sam Steward in Berkeley, California (1991 July 10).
  - Paris Review no. 37, featuring New Rorem, Paris Diary selections, 1966 Spring (Box 12)
  - Steward, ledger of literary income, 1983-1993 (Box 12)
  - The Gay Engagement Calendar, featuring Sam Steward photo for April 12-18, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Wool patch, one bar with knot and eagle (Box 12)
  - Closing Remarks, typescript revision - bound (Box 12)
  - Gertrude and Alice, typescript revision - bound (Box 12)
  - Autobiography, corrected typescript - 211 pages (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous note from "S" to "Katie", 1969 October 9 (Box 12)
  - Thorton Wilder: His World - a biography, by Linda Simon, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Autobiographical typescript with sticky notes - 368 pages (Box 19 (Oversize))
  - My Brother, My Self, with author's holograph corrections, 2 (Box 13)
  - Below the Belt, working manuscript, page proofs F and B, holograph corrections, 3 (Box 13)
  - Steward Rolodex (Box 20)
  - Tattoo shop advertisement board (Box 21 (Oversize))
  - Rocco's Horoscope Calendar, 1969 (Box 21 (Oversize))
  - Dennis Forbes, pen and ink cartoon of Thorton Wilder, inscribed, circa 1981 (Box 21 (Oversize))
  - ("Michael Walters"). The Homosexual's Adjustment - 9 pages typescript, some matted (Box 21 (Oversize))
  - Biographical clipping on Steward, matted (Box 21 (Oversize))
  - Two color photographs of a nude male, matted (Box 21 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook of clippings relating to Angels on the Bough and Washington State University scandal, 1930s (Box 22 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook of clippings relating to Dear Sammy, 1970s (Box 22 (Oversize))
  - 4 leather whips and two leather straps (Box 23 (Oversize))
  - Accujac (case and pump) (Box 24)
  - Stud file (Box 25)
    Metal file box containing notecards cataloging Steward's sexual partners
  - Items found in the back of Stud file
    - Key to Room 111 from the Hotel Medford, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, circa 1940s (Box 32)
    - Ledger compiling information from the Stud file, 1941-1945 (Box 32)
    - Ledger compiling information from the Stud file, 1945-1947 (Box 32)
    - Various items from the Stud file, circa 1948-1952 (Box 32)
      Includes three sheets of papers compiling sex information, and a key to abbreviations, for the years 1950, 1951 and 1952. Also includes: a note entitled "Rope" with the names of men on it, a clipping entitled "Sex Expert In For Test on Sanity" (circa 1948), and an enveloped labeled "J M" containing pubic hair (?).
  - Arnett, Chuck, drawing inscribed to Steward which illustrated Andros story in Drummer magazine 600 - framed (Box 26 (Oversize))
  - Tom of Finland repro postcard (Box 27 (Oversize))
  - Thomas Mann original photograph, inscribed, 1938 (Box 27 (Oversize))
  - Van Vechten, portrait of Gertrude Stein, inscribed by Stein, 1934 (Box 27 (Oversize))
  - Outlook National Lesbian & Gay Quarterly award, 1990 March 3 (Box 27 (Oversize))
  - Bent wire sculpure of motorcylist (man's profile), aluminum tubing (Box 28 (Oversize))
  - Video recordings, 1991; 3 (Box 29)
    3 VHS cassettes: Rick X talks to Sam Steward in Berkeley, California (1991 July 10)
    - Rick X talks to Sam Steward, Berkeley California, CCTV, Box 790, New York NY, 1991 July 10; GENMSS987_0001; 1; 01:03:27 (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102317055)
    - Rick X talks to Sam Steward, Berkeley California, CCTV, Box 790, New York NY, 1991 July 10; GENMSS987_0002; 1; This is a duplicate of GENMSS987_0001. It has not been digitized. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102317063)
    - Rick X talks to Sam Steward, Berkeley California, CCTV, Box 790, New York NY, 1991 July 10; GENMSS987_0003; 1; This is a duplicate of GENMSS987_0001. It has not been digitized. (Box 29, Item barcode 39002102317071)
- August 2012 Acquisition, 1959, undated; 0.08; (1 box)
  - 29 pen and ink tracings of illustrations by Jean Cocteau, for Querelle by Jean Genet (Box 30 (Oversize))
  - Ink and wash Christmas card (Box 30 (Oversize))
  - Charcoal drawing of Alice B. Toklas, 1959 (Box 30 (Oversize))
  - Pen and ink drawing of male nude from a letter to George Platt Lynes (Box 30 (Oversize))
- October 2012 Acquisition, 1960s-1991; 0.21; (1 box)
  - "Angelo" - typescript, facsimile in folder, 1960s (Box 31)
  - "Official" duty - typescript, page 1, circa 1982 (Box 31)
  - "Seven studs" artwork with note from Sasha to Steward, 1991 August 14 (Box 31)